bigmachines.com 2012-05-24

# Privacy

BigMachines, Inc. has created this privacy statement ("Statement") in order to demonstrate our commitment to privacy. Privacy on the bigmachines.com Web Site (the "Site") is of great importance to us. Because we gather important information from our visitors and customers, we have established this Statement to communicate our information gathering and dissemination practices. 

**Collected Information:** In order to access certain portions of the Site, you will be required to register by providing certain limited information regarding you and the company you represent. BigMachines, Inc. may use the information that we collect to contact visitors to further discuss their interest in our company and the services and products we provide and to send information regarding our company, service and product offerings, such as newsletters and events. Visitor email addresses and any personal customer information will not be distributed or shared with any third parties in any circumstance. Customers can opt out of being contacted by us, or receiving such information from us, at any time by visiting http://www.bigmachines.com/emailoptout.php , or sending an email to marketing@bigmachines.com. 

**Cookies:** When you interact with our Site, we strive to make that experience easy and meaningful. Our Web server may send a cookie to the computer of our Site visitors. Cookies are files that Web browsers place on a computer's hard drive and are used to tell us whether customers and visitors have visited the Site previously. Standing alone, cookies do not identify you personally. They merely recognize your browser. Unless you choose to identify yourself to BigMachines, Inc., either by requesting a download or registering for a demo or webinar, you remain anonymous to BigMachines, Inc. If you choose not to accept cookies from the domain "bigmachines.com", you will still be able to access the entire Site, however you will be required to re-register each time you would like to access those portions of the Site which require registration. 

When we send messages to you or others, we may provide a link that contains an identifier, which allows us to identify the person to whom we sent the message, record whether the email has been open and set a cookie so we can link non-personal data to their email address. We do this in order to tailor our communication for that individual. 

**Log Files:** We use visitor's IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the Site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. BigMachines occasionally matches these IP addresses to publicly-available company IP registries, and BigMachines may contact visiting companies to discuss potential interest in our company. IP addresses that we collect are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

**Users Outside of the United States:** While we make every effort to honor the laws and wishes of all users, this Site is available for users located primarily in the United States of America and therefore may not recognize foreign laws. 

**Safe Harbor Commitment:** BigMachines conforms to the 7 Safe Harbor principles and self-regulates our conformance based on this privacy policy. 

  1. Notice- BigMachines will notify individuals about the purposes for which we collect personal information.
  2. Choice- BigMachines will not share personal information we collect with any outside parties without explicit Opt-In choice by these individuals.
  3. Onward Transfer- BigMachines does not disclose personal information to any outside parties or agents unless those individuals are notified and have given explicit Opt-In choice to allow BigMachines to share their information.
  4. Access- BigMachines will provide any individual access to their personal information we have collected by contacting marketing@bigmachines.com.
  5. Security- BigMachines data is hosted in a secure environment with advanced security technology.
  6. Data Integrity- BigMachines actively monitors the accuracy and reliability of its database.
  7. Enforcement- BigMachines' management team takes this commitment very seriously.

BigMachines, Inc. complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. BigMachines, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view BigMachine’s certification, please visit http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/

In compliance with the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, BigMachines, Inc. commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact BigMachines, Inc. at legal@bigmachines.com

BigMachines, Inc. has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by BigMachines, Inc., please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints for more information and to file a complaint. 

**Security:** BigMachines, Inc. takes precautions to protect data and information under its control from misuse, loss or alteration. BigMachines utilizes some of the most advanced technology for Internet security available today. BigMachines maintains security measures to allow only the appropriate personnel access to your information. Unfortunately, no system can ensure complete security, and BigMachines disclaims any liability resulting from use of the Site. In addition, our Site is hosted in a secure server environment that uses a firewall and other advanced technology to prevent interference or access from outside intruders. 

**BigMachines Customers' Hosted Data:** BigMachines, Inc. delivers a hosted software solution to our customers. Our customers may collect personal information from their customers or prospects which resides in BigMachines data servers at our Hosting Partner sites. This data is owned and maintained by each customer- not by BigMachines. As such, BigMachines makes no claims concerning the privacy policies or Safe Harbor commitments of our customers concerning their data. 

**Links to Third-Party Sites:** The Site contains links to other Web Sites. BigMachines, Inc. is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other Web Sites. Visitors will need to check the policy statement of these others Web Sites to understand their policies. Customers and visitors who access a linked site may be disclosing their private information. It is the responsibility of the user to keep such information private and confidential. 

Questions or Comments Regarding the Privacy Policy For additional questions, or to be taken off our marketing lists, please send an e-mail to marketing@bigmachines.com. 

To be permanently removed from BigMachines mailing list, please click here.
